[engine starts, roars]
[Jerry] This is a 1963 Corvette Stingray
in silver blue,
with a blue interior
and kind of a dark purplish upholstery.
Killer.
It's got a 327 cubic inch V8,
four-barrel carb,
and proper knock-off wheels.
Are there faster Corvettes? Yes.
Are there bigger-engine,
tire-melting Corvettes?
Of course.
Are there cooler Corvettes?
I don't think so.
1963 is the only year
with the split rear window.
This car looks like a submarine.
Like you could drive
right into the water and keep going.
It's edgy, it's stubby,
it's perfectly proportioned,
with just the right amount of detail
and just the right stance.
In the '60s and '70s,
all American astronauts
in the space program drove Corvettes.
When you drive a Saturn V at work,
you cannot get out of that
and into a Country Squire wagon.
Look at the scoops. Look at the nose.
Look at the tail.
Look at the door cutouts into the roof.
The idea behind this car
is just confidence.
This came from an American culture
that would just say things and do them
without having any idea how.
"We're gonna put a man on the moon."
"How we gonna do it?
When we gonna do it?
Why are we doing this?" "No idea."
We just did stuff. Crazy, but great.
And I think this cool blue
is just the right color
for my are-you-kidding-me
super-special guest today,
the commander in chief
of the United States of America,
President Barack Obama...
who, in my opinion,
has gotten off just enough funny lines
to qualify for getting on this show.
A few weeks ago,
Dick Cheney says he thinks
I'm the worst president of his lifetime.
[audience laughs]
Which is interesting, because I think
Dick Cheney is the worst president
of my lifetime.
[audience laughing]
-[telephone ringing]
-[man, over phone] White House.
[Jerry] Yes, may I speak
with the president, please?
-[Obama] Speaking.
-[Jerry laughs]
[Jerry] Sir, may I compliment you on
cutting all that red tape in Washington.
So you still up for a coffee?
[Obama] Sure. Why don't you come on by?
It's 1600 Pennsylvania.
[Jerry] Yeah. I know.
I'm Jerry Seinfeld, and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
[Jerry whistling]
[leaves rustling]
[Jerry] You ready?
I got some stuff to do.
[Jerry sighs]
Are these washed?
[Obama chuckling]
Come on, let's go.
Let's go get some coffee.
-Well, don't leave the apple, though...
-[Jerry chuckles]
If you're gonna have a bite,
you've gotta take it.
[Jerry] Okay. Can I throw this out?
You have a garbage?
You have to use
the non-presidential garbage.
Oh, I see.
-[Jerry laughs]
-[Obama] Come on.
[inaudible]
-This is a sweet car right here.
-Okay, now check this out.
This is beautiful.
I thought, the coolest car,
American-made,
for the coolest guy
ever to hold this office.
[Obama] I...
You know what? You are winning
a lot of points with me right now.
[inaudible]
A friend of my grandfather's,
who had this when I was, like,
-I was what, seven or eight or something.
-Right.
And I remember seeing this thing
and thinking,
if I was ever able
to get me one of these...
-Yeah.
-...I'd be set.
-Well, let's hop in. Come on.
-Let's go.
I'm glad you had some free time.
I really like this car.
-Be careful about hitting, uh...
-Oh.
-[Obama] You look nervous.
-I'm a little nervous.
-Are you always this nervous?
-No, this is a little different.
-Like with Fallon and Letterman?
-It's not the same.
-No. It's not the same.
-It's not as stressful.
[Jerry] We're just gonna run out
for a quick coffee.
-We'll be right back.
-I'm sorry. That's not possible.
I do this little show,
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
You're a comedian with the president
going nowhere.
-Back it up.
-Yes, sir.
[Jerry] Do you ever think
about every person you talk to
is putting on an act, a total show?
-It's a problem.
-[Jerry laughs]
Don't you think every American child
is a president fan?
You grow up loving the president.
I do really well
with the zero to eight demographic.
-Oh, really?
-Yeah. They love me.
-Partly 'cause I think my ears are big.
-[Jerry laughing]
And so I look
a little like a cartoon character.
-Right.
-And then little kids love saying my name.
-Right. That's funny.
-But it's all one big name.
It's Barackobama.
[Jerry] It is one of those names
that you could compress into one word.
-One word. Barackobama.
-It's good.
It's like a Nickelodeon thing.
[Jerry] Well, anything "orama" is fun.
[Obama laughing]
This is called The Beast.
It's a Caddy, basically on a tank frame.
-[Jerry] Oh, my God.
-Yeah, see?
So, I could call a nuclear submarine
right here from this...
-I'll bet you don't have that in your car.
-I don't have that.
Yeah, it's a cool feature.
Plus, seat warmers.
-So, between the nuclear submarine thing--
-Well, everybody's got that. Yeah.
Is that right? That's standard now?
That's pretty standard
everywhere now, yeah.
[both laughing]
This I like, though. I'm gonna get that.
You can't have that.
What is it that you really want to do
that they don't let you do?
I would love to just be taking a walk,
and then I run into you,
you're sitting on a bench. Right?
-Now I see--
-And suddenly I say,
"Hey, Jerry, how you doing?"
You say, "I'm doing pretty good.
-What are you doing?"
-"Nothing. It's a Saturday morning."
Right.
-That moment when you lost your anonymity.
-Mmm-hmm.
And anonymity is not something
you think about as being valuable.
-With all due respect...
-Yeah.
I remember very well not being famous.
-You think it was okay?
-It wasn't that great.
-Yeah?
-It was...
You think being famous is better?
-Yes?
-Yeah.
[both laughing]
I always wanted to be
in a show about nothing,
and here I am.
There's nothing
more nothing than this. Nothing.
Come on, let's go get some coffee.
[Jerry] So, when you were a kid,
did you have favorite presidents?
Teddy Roosevelt is a cool character.
In fact, he may be the guy who
would be the most fun to hang out with.
He just does crazy stuff.
[Obama] Mmm.
-[Jerry] So--
-That's just a little, a little gin.
-[Jerry laughs]
-I take midday.
You were asking...
You were asking what part of the day,
-what part of the day--
-Yeah, when--
-It's right about now.
-Yeah. That gives you a little zip?
[Obama] Teddy Roosevelt would go up to
Yellowstone Park for, like, a month,
and nobody knew where he was,
nobody could get in touch with him.
-Can you imagine that?
-Wait a minute. In office?
In office. Sounds pretty good to me.
[Jerry] Boy, that's a lot of messages
when you get back.
-How do you get up?
-[Obama] Uh...
-Do you need an alarm?
-Somebody calls me.
You get a wake-up call?
Yeah. Why not?
[Jerry] Get out of bed--
So, I brush my teeth, shave,
put on some workout clothes.
I go up, work out.
Shave, then work out.
Yeah, I believe in shaving
before the workout.
Okay.
Because that's how I do it,
and I don't really need a reason.
[Jerry] I see.
I guess I'll just make some myself.
Let's see you make coffee.
How far can you wander around up there
in your underwear?
How far can you get before there's,
like, people and it's not cool?
It's not cool, generally,
wandering around in my underwear.
Can you really get a good night's...
Isn't this like Night at the Museum
when you go to sleep here?
First night was.
Of all the jarring elements
of first being elected president.
You know, you've got the inauguration,
and there are two million people,
and there are parades,
and there's this and there's that,
all the hoopla.
The thing that really does get to you
is, after all that's over,
and it's the first night,
and you're sleeping in the White House.
-Right. Right.
-It's not like a hotel room.
Right.
So, you're looking around
and you're thinking,
-"What the hell is this?"
-[laughs]
-Right?
-Yeah.
-Night at the Museum.
That's how it feels
probably the first week.
There's a lot of crazy stuff
that's happened in this house.
There is, yeah.
Does that ever enter your mind?
-Sometimes it does.
-Yeah.
There are times where you think,
"Okay, here's where
-Kennedy was hanging out."
-Right.
Or "Here's where Nixon
was talking to Haldeman
-about whatever they were talking about."
-Right. Yeah, yeah.
Can you adjust the temperature
in here at all?
Is there a therm-- Have you ever
touched a thermostat in here?
No, I make a call.
You make a call. [laughs]
If I slid open your underwear drawer,
one brand or a number of brands?
-You gotta go with one brand.
-One brand. One color?
Yeah, of course.
This is a critical concept.
It's more work that you don't need.
How many suits do they put out
in the morning?
Well, they don't put out suits.
I have a closet like normal people.
-You pick the suit?
-I do.
[chuckles] Yes.
-Really?
-I do. I do.
I would have a guy just leave the...
Same with the lunch.
Here's the suit, here's the lunch.
Well, with the suit,
I only have blue and gray suits.
-Right. No black?
-I have one black suit.
Black's too rough for a president.
You gotta soften it a little.
-Well, but I'm a cool president, so--
-Right. That's true.
What's the coolest
president commemoration?
-Oh, okay. That's interesting.
-To get?
'Cause you're in line
to get something great.
The Rushmore thing...
-Rushmore?
-...would be interesting,
but that's pretty exclusive real estate.
You know what I noticed about
Mount Rushmore?
Washington has totally turned his back
on those other three guys.
[laughing]
[stammers] I--
-He is in a different angle.
-Yeah.
Have you ever had one of those
George W. Bush...
Remember when he couldn't
find the door in the wall?
-Yeah.
-And he was just looking for the door?
I don't ever believe
that publicly you've had one of those.
I have not had a public moment like that.
-You haven't tumbled down a stair?
-No. Not yet.
You never leaned over
and just started vomiting in Japan?
-No. Nothing like that's happened so far.
-Nothing?
What's your most embarrassing
president moment?
This may be it.
[Jerry laughs]
You're one of those guys,
even though you seem very relaxed,
you gotta go off at some point with food.
-What's your thing--
-Nachos.
Would a tray of-- Nachos.
That's one of those
where I have to have it taken away.
-I'll have guacamole...
-It's the greatest.
-...coming out of my eyeballs.
-Yeah.
People you spend most of your time with,
are they really smart?
Or are they mostly headstrong,
agenda-laden idiots?
You know, when you're
dealing with Congress, uh, it varies.
There are gonna be some folks there
that are foolish.
Mmm-hmm.
-Just like there are in comedy or...
-Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
Well, everyone in comedy is foolish.
All my friends are knuckleheads.
-All of 'em?
-All of 'em.
I know some of your friends.
Did I tell you I played golf
with Larry David?
No, 'cause you and I don't talk that much.
I love Larry.
When we play golf,
he's a fair-skinned guy, which is--
[groans] The sunscreen.
-He lathers himself in sunscreen.
-I can't take it, I know.
It's gross.
It's dripping,
and it's caked white all over.
It catches parts of his ears,
-and there's globs of it.
-It's horrible. Yeah.
What sport is politics?
Is it chess? Is it liar's poker?
That's interesting.
That was a good question.
It's probably most like football.
-Football?
-Yeah.
Because a lot of players,
-a lot of specialization, lot of hitting.
-Right.
-Lot of attrition.
-A lot of attrition.
Um, but then, every once in a while,
you'll see an opening.
-Uh-huh.
-Right? So you're gonna be...
You hit the line, you get one yard.
-Right.
-You try a play, you get sacked.
-Now it's, like, third and 15.
-Mmm-hmm.
But every once in a while...
You have to punt a lot.
But every once in a while,
you'll see a hole,
and then there's open field.
How many world leaders do you think
are just completely out of their mind?
A pretty sizable percent.
[laughing]
Some of these people, you must meet them,
you'll just be chatting,
and you see in the eyes.
You look in the eyes, you go,
"Oh, this guy's gone."
Yeah. Well, and part of what happens is
these guys,
I think, the longer they stay in office,
the more likely that is to happen.
-Of course.
-Right?
-They lose it.
-Yeah.
I mean, at a certain point, your feet hurt
and you're having trouble peeing...
-[Jerry laughs]
-...you have absolute power and--
-Privilege is toxic.
-Yeah.
-Sadly. Sadly.
-It really is.
-Things that people struggle to achieve--
-Yeah.
They get to positions of power,
influence, money,
-can do things...
-Right.
It has a toxic effect on their judgment.
Yes. Has that happened to you yet?
-No.
-Why is that do you think?
-Let me ask you some questions.
-Yeah, why don't you ask me some--
Yeah, come on. You do some work.
-So, you're a funny guy.
-Thank you.
You go on some late-night talk shows,
people think you're funny,
they give you a show.
-Right.
-And then next thing you know,
you've made a ridiculous amount of money.
So much more than you.
And yet, how do I seem to you?
Do I seem spoiled, out-of-touch?
Well, I don't know.
You have a pretty good instinct
for people.
Right now,
you seem like a completely normal guy.
But I'm putting on an act,
like everyone else does for you.
-That's my point.
-[Jerry laughs]
That's what I'm getting at,
but I'm gonna probe this.
Uh, the question is,
how did you calibrate
dealing with that? Right?
-Well--
-At a certain point,
you might have thought to yourself,
"You know what,
-I'm more than just a comedian."
-Nah.
"I'm gonna make a Jewish version
of Citizen Kane."
You know? How did you keep perspective?
-I'll give you the real answer.
-Yeah.
It's gotta be similar to your life.
I fell in love with the work,
and the work--
-Saved you.
-Was joyful--
-Yeah.
-And difficult and interesting,
and that was my focus.
So, now that you're like
a quasi-retired man of leisure.
-I work a lot.
-Do you?
-Yeah.
-Are you still doing stand-up?
Are you still making speeches?
Do you still get hecklers?
-What's your theory of handling hecklers?
-Sympathy.
I say, "You know what? You seem upset."
[laughing]
"I'm so sorry.
I know that's not why you came in here.
-Let's talk."
-[laughing]
What kind of language do people use?
-What kind of language--
-English.
-As a general rule.
-Yeah.
-That's funny.
-[laughing]
Does it help with your stress level?
-'Cause it helps mine.
-I curse.
-"This son of a bitch."
-I say...
-"This rat bastard comes in here..."
-You blow off a little steam, right?
-Yeah.
Bad stuff or stupid stuff
is happening constantly, right? Every day.
So, you have to be able
to just make fun of...
-"Wow, that..."
-Yeah, of course.
"That was even dumber
and more annoying than usual."
That's when, uh...
cursing is really valuable, right?
All right. We just--
-Are we done?
-We're about done.
Only problem is
I didn't work in Obamacare.
Usually, the only reason I do these things
is 'cause I'm promoting health care.
Yeah... But if you want, go ahead.
No. I mean,
if you don't want to sully your show...
I don't mind. I really don't mind.
...with the interest of getting people
with no health care,
signing up, so that, heaven forbid,
something happens to 'em--
It's a great thing.
Please try Obamacare today.
[laughing]
That was fun.
[inaudible]
I want to give you a shot
to drive this car.
You know what, this is a childhood dream.
This is outstanding.
Yeah.
You ever go on eBay?
[Obama] No.
Let's do this then.
-Yeah, baby!
-[Jerry laughing]
-Watch out, people.
-[Jerry laughs]
-All righty.
-That's great.
I like the hand hanging over the wheel.
Yeah, yeah. No, I mean, that's...
If you're driving a 'Vette,
gotta be doing it that way.
-You can't be doing the...
-Yeah, no, no, no.
...the "12 and 2" thing.
No, that's not cool. Come on, man.
I'm appreciably cooler
-than I was just two minutes ago.
-Yeah.
I bet if you talk to the guy,
they'll let us out.
Just say, you know, "I'm the president,
and I'm gonna be out for a quick coffee."
Hey, Darrell,
-can you open this up--
-Sir, I'm sorry, I can't allow it.
That's unbelievable.
Golly.
I knew that wouldn't work.
You didn't sell it.
He's gonna be lurking
through the bushes?
-[woman] He's gonna be peeking at you.
-Harry, don't, uh...
-Don't shoot him.
-I won't.
He's a very funny guy. We all like him.
My poll numbers would go down
if you did harm to Jerry Seinfeld.